<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An English winding-sheet for the East-India manufactors in a letter to a person of quality.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 34 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A38483</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E3124</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R3589</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12413124</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12413124</idno>
            <idno type="VID">61602</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A38483)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 61602)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 938:12)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An English winding-sheet for the East-India manufactors in a letter to a person of quality.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>7, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Cambridge University Library.</note>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>East India Company.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Commerce --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>Geremy Carnes</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb facs="tcp:61602:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:61602:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>AN <hi>Engliſh VVinding-Sheet</hi> FOR THE <hi>Eaſt-India MAN<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>FACTORS.</hi>
            </head>
            <head type="sub">In a Letter to a Perſon of QUALITY.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>YOUR Acknowledgment of the ſatisfaction You have re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived by the peruſal of the ſeveral Late Printed Tracts, That the free Admiſſion of the Home-Conſumption of <hi>Eaſt-India.</hi> Wrought Silks, almoſt hath, and will certainly be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come the utter Subverſion of the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Silk-Manufacturers, both (Weavers and Throwſters) at <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Canterbury,</hi> and wherever it is ſetled. But your doubt, Whether the Exportation of thoſe <hi>Eaſt-India Wrought Silks</hi> that now are, and may be ſtill Exported, have not, and may not be of greater Advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage to <hi>England,</hi> than the Silk <hi>Manufactury <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ere</hi> is, or can be; and that the <hi>Prohibiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n</hi> of the Wearing them here will not <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eſtroy this Advantage that hath, and may be made by their <hi>Exportation,</hi> and ſo Obſtruct and Hinder a more Publick Benefit to the Kingdom, than the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervation of all the Silk-Manufacturers are to <hi>England.</hi> And this, you ſay, is the great Pretence and Plea of the <hi>Eaſt-India Traders,</hi> and that then we muſt buy Wrought <hi>Silks</hi> at much <hi>dearer Rates,</hi> if their <hi>Trade</hi> herein be Obſtructed, and likewiſe whether if we ſhould procure all other Neceſſary Manufactures in like manner (both for Home-Conſumption and Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portation) Plentiful and Cheap from <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dia,</hi> it might not be greatly to our <hi>Advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage,</hi> all which, if <hi>our ſelves</hi> do not, the <hi>Dutch</hi> will impoſe upon us, under pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence of their own Works, and like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe by Exporting them to all other parts, Gain the profit thereof from us, which is the matter wherein you deſire farther Satisfaction and Information.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>SIR,</hi> In Anſwer to which pray con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider, for I am ſure theſe Objections are as Falſe as Impolytick (we have already, and are now inciting the <hi>Indians,</hi> and <hi>Chinees</hi> that are a numerous and Labo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious People, and can and do live, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Fire or Clothing and with a Tri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vial Expence for Food) to load us with their Manufactures, that are utterly de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtructive of our own, and our very be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a People of any Number or Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue, by our not only conſuming their handy-work our ſelves in the Room of our own Silk and Wooll-Manufactures, or ſuch as are the Return thereof; but likewiſe by the hindring or ſpoiling all our Foreign Exportations we uſed to have for thoſe our own Fine Goods, and then plead it as a Meritorious, and Advantageous Act, thus to help forward our own deſtruction with both hands; for had we not puſht forward the <hi>Indian</hi> Trade, our own <hi>Engliſh</hi> Wrought Goods had (as formerly ſerved the World and gained that profit) in the Room of thoſe we falſly pretend this Advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tageous Exportation of <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Manufactures do produce; ſo that all thoſe <hi>Indian</hi> Exportations are double loſs, rather than any profit to <hi>England,</hi> which hath for ſeveral Years paſt come to that <hi>Perfection</hi> in all <hi>Wrought, Figur'd and Flower'd Silks,</hi> and Stuffs, as far to outdo <hi>Holland,</hi> and Vye with <hi>France,</hi>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:61602:2"/>or any part of the <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>niverſe,</hi> and with thoſe, had not we our ſelves occaſion'd the contrary (as before ſpecified) have ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved many Countries, with which it is worth our while to Trade; which are chiefly our own <hi>Weſtern Plantations, Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, Scotland,</hi> and <hi>Spain,</hi> except which, our Exports herein have been to little advantage; for what is of <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Wrought-Silks Exported for <hi>Holland,</hi> is ſaid (by thoſe that underſtand their dealing) chiefly with deſign to ſave the draw-back Duty, by <hi>ſtealing</hi> them in again <hi>Cuſtom free,</hi> which if they can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not, they frequently re-enter, and turn them again upon us.</p>
            <p>In the ſerving our own Plantations with Silks and Stuffs, 'tis greatly im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>polytick, that any particular Perſon's <hi>Advantage,</hi> and the Benefit of the <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dian</hi> ſhould be preferr'd before the <hi>Kingdoms,</hi> elſe they might be obliged to nothing of <hi>Silks,</hi> and <hi>Stuffs,</hi> but of <hi>Engliſh make;</hi> but in the ſtead thereof we allow them the draw-back in <hi>Eaſt-India Silks,</hi> greatly to our own preju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nice, and ſo are no advantage to the Government neither, and the prejudice <hi>England</hi> doth ſuſtain in this <hi>Single Arti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cle,</hi> I believe to be greater than the profit of the Exports all the <hi>Indian Wrought-Silks</hi> amount to.</p>
            <p>And as we have encouraged the <hi>Indi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans</hi> to the increaſing and making multi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tudes of <hi>Wrought-Silks,</hi> as I ſhall preſently inſtance; ſo we have not only <hi>Conſum'd them our ſelves,</hi> and ſerved our own Plan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations; but courted and obliged all thoſe parts we deal to, to the Uſe and Conſumption thereof. But the Prejudice <hi>England</hi> hath, and doth receive thereby, being added <hi>to the former Article,</hi> when we conſider that all our <hi>Engliſh Wrought Silks</hi> is the rerurn of our Woollen Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nufacture, and Multitudes of <hi>People</hi> like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe employ'd, it muſt far out-ballance all pretended profit of <hi>India Wrought Silks,</hi> which are the Exportations pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſed with our good hard <hi>Silver,</hi> when as we had otherwiſe ſerved thoſe parts with Silks of our <hi>own Manufacturing,</hi> which had kept, and increaſed our Numbers ten times more than now they are.</p>
            <p>Yet do we not contend to prevent our Merchants Exportation, if the <hi>European</hi> World will not be content without them, but if by our uſe of <hi>Engliſh Wrought Silks,</hi> other Kingdoms will follow our Example, as I think it is one of the greateſt Bleſſings we can hope for our good, <hi>I only pray God they may not be miſtaken</hi> that fear it; for the advantage <hi>England</hi> will reap by gaining a preferrence to our own Manufactur'd Silks, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> will be far greater benefit to the <hi>Kingdom,</hi> than the Exportation of thoſe <hi>Indian Silks, &amp;c.</hi> that will go in their ſtead. And I am ſorry any <hi>Engliſhman</hi> ſhould <hi>grudge</hi> it; but whatever their pretences be, of vaſt Exportations when it ſerves their purpoſe, we have their own Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion in print that <hi>Two thirds</hi> of all Wrought Silks Imported, were con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſum'd in <hi>England;</hi> but they freely and moſt truly ſince that acknowledged be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the <hi>Honourable Houſe of Lords,</hi> that <hi>Nine Tenths</hi> thereof were in <hi>England</hi> ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pended, which is ſufficient proof what ſmall advantage <hi>England</hi> can reap by their Exportations of <hi>Wrought Silks,</hi> not to be near anſwerable to the Damage they do the <hi>Kingdom</hi> by the prejudice to the <hi>Turky and Italian Merchants,</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides the forementioned innumerable <hi>Manufacturers.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>As to your Query, Whether the like advantage may not accrue to <hi>England</hi> by the Importation, Conſumption, and Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porting of all other <hi>India Manufactures.</hi> I dare be poſitive, That as in the Caſe of <hi>India</hi> Wrought <hi>Silks,</hi> all their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nufactures hereafter mention'd, or any other which we are poſſeſt of, or that we can have from other <hi>parts</hi> in return for our <hi>Engliſh</hi> Productions and <hi>Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factures,</hi> is prejudicial to the Welfare of <hi>England.</hi> As for what is again Exported, it cannot hurt us, but as it hinders the Sale of our own Productions and <hi>Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factures</hi> (and therein it doth) which would certainly otherwiſe Vend in thoſe parts, to which thoſe <hi>Indian</hi> Goods are ſo Exported; but this we conteſt not in
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:61602:2"/>the Matter of Silks for our <hi>ſelves.</hi> But let what Goods will be made in <hi>India,</hi> and come, let us not conſume them <hi>here</hi> to our own prejudice, or in giving the <hi>Example,</hi> nor ſend them to ſuch places as we may oblige to take our own <hi>Manufactures,</hi> I mean our own <hi>Weſtern Plantations,</hi> let <hi>other parts</hi> of the <hi>European</hi> World look to themſelves, and ſhare them amongſt 'em; the damage will light on <hi>ſome,</hi> and by this doing, we ſhall wiſely Support our <hi>Wealth,</hi> Imploy and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſe our <hi>Numbers</hi> of People which will keep up the Value of <hi>Lands.</hi> As to the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms paying dearer for <hi>Engliſh Wrought Silks,</hi> 'tis a needleſs fear; for if men of Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance hath but reaſonable encourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to venture their Stocks in the Silk <hi>Manufactory,</hi> we ſhall ſoon make ſuch Mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tititudes of <hi>Workmen,</hi> as ſhall enable us to ſell better Penny-worths than the <hi>Eaſt-India Merchants</hi> do, and this will be far better for the good of the <hi>Kingdom,</hi> than to let them be as at preſent about <hi>London,</hi> reduc'd to a <hi>Tenth</hi> of what they were, and at <hi>Canter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bury</hi> to an <hi>Eighth</hi> of our former Numbers.</p>
            <p>As for the <hi>Dutch,</hi> or other, ſerving us with <hi>India</hi> Goods, under pretence of their own Manufacture, 'tis an Objection that hath been ſufficiently Anſwered, and hath little of weight in it, unleſs we give up our ſelves to deſpair, rather than contend with any Difficulty, that may as eaſily be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vented, as <hi>French</hi> Alamodes and Luſtrings, if <hi>Engliſhmen</hi> can have but the ſame favour as the <hi>French</hi> of that Alamode and Luſtring Company have had.</p>
            <p>And as to the <hi>Exportations</hi> of ſuch <hi>East-India Silks,</hi> &amp;c. if they be made and muſt come, better we ſerve the <hi>European parts</hi> than any other; but 'tis plain, That all Manufacturing <hi>parts</hi> of the World are ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king the Alarm, and ſtanding on their <hi>Guard;</hi> and this makes the <hi>Eaſt-India Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants</hi> ſo zealous for a home <hi>Conſumption;</hi> and 'tis We, of all <hi>Kingdoms</hi> in <hi>Europe</hi> that deſerve the greateſt blame, for the ſake of a little private profit, to bring this part of the World into this <hi>Streight;</hi> for it was not the <hi>Dutch,</hi> but the <hi>Engliſh,</hi> that firſt put the <hi>Indians</hi> on that vaſt increaſe of Silk-<hi>worms</hi> (as much to the Detriment of the <hi>Turky</hi> and Clothing Trade, as is the farther Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nufacturing thereof a great loſs to <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> tho' never ſo cheap ſold to the <hi>India Merchants</hi> if purchaſed with our <hi>money,</hi> to the prejudice of the forementioned par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties) it was the <hi>Engliſh</hi> that put them on the farther Improvement, to that great Exceſs they are now at of <hi>Throwing Dying, and Weaving,</hi> when both they and the <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dians</hi> could not do leſs than laugh in their <hi>Sleeves</hi> at the Act that prevents <hi>Throwing and Dying,</hi> (the profit thereof being wholly Loſs to us, and Gain to <hi>India,</hi> in being af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Wrought into <hi>Silks</hi>) it was only the <hi>Engliſh</hi> that ſent over Artiſts of all theſe Trades, and <hi>Pattern-drawers,</hi> and <hi>Patterns</hi> that might ſute the <hi>European</hi> Humours; and in plain <hi>Engliſh,</hi> it was the <hi>Engliſh,</hi> it is the <hi>Engliſh,</hi> and it will be the <hi>Engliſh,</hi> that will be the only <hi>mad part of the World,</hi> in this reſpect, if not by <hi>Law</hi> prevented, Strict Edicts in <hi>France</hi> prevent their Home-Conſumption; <hi>Flanders</hi> and <hi>Venice,</hi> and all other parts do the like; and we above all others have great reaſon to do ſo too; and 'tis high time, and how the Caſe now is, and hereafter will be, with us, is what I ſhall briefly demonſtrate to you and the conſequence hereof (having with all brevi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſatisfied each part of your Objection) by which it will appear, That we had better prohibit all Trade with <hi>India,</hi> than go for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward as now doing and projecting.</p>
            <p>As to what we are now doing, 'tis vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible to all that obſerve how the <hi>Fancy and Humour</hi> of the <hi>Female Sex,</hi> with the advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage the <hi>Late Law</hi> hath given, inclines ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral men of great <hi>Stocks,</hi> and many of them out of Neceſſity, and againſt their <hi>Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments and Inclination,</hi> meerly for the im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployment of their <hi>Eſtates</hi> to advantage, to ſtrike into this pernicious <hi>India Trade;</hi> ſo that the <hi>Vogue</hi> and <hi>Cry,</hi> (under the Notion, of <hi>publick good.</hi> Working backward) is like our Watermen with <hi>a hye India, hye India, hye,</hi> to almoſt a total Neglect and Diſre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect of the Good and Welfare of the <hi>Turky,</hi> and other more advantageous <hi>Trades of England,</hi> with a Subverſion of our moſt profitable <hi>Manufactures;</hi> for as they have left the <hi>Imbroiders</hi> little more than a Name, and both <hi>Cabbinet</hi> and <hi>Fan-makers</hi> are for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced to be contented to become their <hi>Job<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers</hi>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:61602:3"/>and Broakers, by Applauding and Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vancing the price of thoſe Commodities, that are the ruin of numbers of their Trade. So they ſeem to aim at the deſtruction of all they can. The poor <hi>Button-makers</hi> in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed are ſecur'd by Law (if that will do) elſe we might have expected whole <hi>Cargoes</hi> of that <hi>Commodity.</hi> As for the <hi>Ribbond-makers</hi> (in which many of the Undone <hi>Broad Silk Weavers</hi> hoped to take Sanctua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry.) Their Cake is <hi>Dough;</hi> for the <hi>Indian</hi> Merchant have ſet the <hi>Indians</hi> thereon, and now bring them (though <hi>prohibited by Law</hi>) from <hi>India,</hi> and are entred at the Cuſtom-houſe, under the denomination of Parcels of <hi>Wrought Silks,</hi> and that lately one par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cel was <hi>ſeized,</hi> and is in the <hi>Cuſtom-houſe Warehouſe;</hi> and I hope will not eſcape due <hi>Proſecution,</hi> but that the <hi>Cuſtom-houſe Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners</hi> will take care to regulate ſuch <hi>dark Entries.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>They are now upon a Trial of Skill with the <hi>Shoemakers,</hi> their being two parcels lately come for a <hi>Sample;</hi> and doubtleſs, conſidering what empty Hould their Ships carry to <hi>India,</hi> it will be worth their while to carry our <hi>Leather,</hi> if they have it not there: For <hi>Elevenpence</hi> in the Shilling ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved in the <hi>Workmanſhip</hi> may make it ſo, though they have not the advantage of Ninepence more in the Shilling, as they have in the <hi>Weaving Materials.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now by what hath been done, and is now doing, we may certainly conclude what theſe <hi>India Traders</hi> will hereafter do if not reſtrained; and as they have already almoſt <hi>ſwallowed</hi> and <hi>ingroſſed</hi> the Silk-<hi>Wea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving, Throwing,</hi> and Fan-making of <hi>England,</hi> brought all our <hi>Cabinet-making</hi> into con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt; they will by the ſame ways and means ruin all <hi>Trades and Manufacturies,</hi> which their intereſt may tempt them to do.</p>
            <p>The very <hi>Mercers,</hi> they ſtrive to ſpoil, by their ſetting up Retail Warehouſes, and if not prevented, they will, if poſſible, effect it.</p>
            <p>Now when they break in already upon thoſe that have Laws for their Security, as in the Caſe of <hi>Thrown and Dy'd Silk, im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>broidry, Ribbons,</hi> &amp;c. no <hi>Trades</hi> that they can profit by are like to eſcape them. Their plenty of <hi>Copper</hi> and <hi>Tynn</hi> will give them opportunity to ruin both our <hi>Bra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiers</hi> and <hi>Pewterers,</hi> and <hi>Tynn-men</hi> and <hi>Mines.</hi> The <hi>Joyners</hi> and <hi>Carvers,</hi> they have pretty well encroach'd upon; and though Modiſh Garments from <hi>France</hi> was always accounted grievous to us; yet from <hi>Eaſt-India,</hi> Multitudes of them are brought to the great prejudice of the <hi>Taylors.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And 'tis impoſſible, but that from the Cheapneſs both of Silk and Cotton, and other Materials ſit for <hi>Stockings,</hi> they muſt in courſe ruin our moſt ingenious <hi>Art</hi> of <hi>Frame-Working,</hi> and Needle-knitting, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs they become very ſelf-denying.</p>
            <p>That whole <hi>Cargoes</hi> of all manner of <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pholſtrys</hi> is preparing, and that our <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>p<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holſterers</hi> ſhall have the benefit of ſetting them up, will be a mercy to them, more than the <hi>Weavers</hi> have.</p>
            <p>That their <hi>Shoes</hi> will be as highly eſteem'd as their <hi>Silks,</hi> their is no Que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtion, and that Multitudes of them will ſhortly arrive, is out of doubt.</p>
            <p>How much of our <hi>Sempſtreſſes</hi> work is already ſwallowed up every <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Sale demonſtrates; and that there will be a further Encroachment thereon, is moſt certain; and whether all the <hi>money</hi> that purchaſeth <hi>Chyna Ware,</hi> be not loſt to the <hi>Kingdom,</hi> unleſs Exported (for the farther profit of <hi>Europe</hi>) beſides the prejudice it will do the ingenious <hi>Potter</hi> and <hi>Glaſs-makers</hi> of <hi>England,</hi> may be well worth our Conſideration.</p>
            <p>Our <hi>Limners</hi> are like to be outdone by <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>gly faces,</hi> and all their pieces ſhall be more admired for their <hi>deformity;</hi> and 'tis no doubt but in a ſhort time you ſhall have whole Auctions of them.</p>
            <p>And that our <hi>workers</hi> in <hi>iron</hi> and <hi>ſteel;</hi> which Commodity will lie more cloſe than that of Wood, ſhall in little time eſcape better than the <hi>Silk Manufactures.</hi> is very improbable, which will render that ingenious diſcovery of the Slitting-mill (for the which this <hi>Kingdom</hi> muſt ever be obliged to the Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mory of the Folio's) of little advantage; for though the <hi>Indians</hi> have not yet attained unto it; yet doubtleſs our publick ſpirited <hi>Traders</hi> will not fail to carry it thither, and <hi>barrs of Iron</hi> from hence will make Excel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent ballaſt for their <hi>Ships,</hi> if they have it not
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:61602:3"/>there, which matters not much, the prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cipal coſt being Workmanſhip, in which 11<hi>d in the Shilling</hi> being ſaved, will in like manner be of vaſt advantage to <hi>England,</hi> and ſpare all our <hi>Burningham</hi> and <hi>Sheffield</hi> Workmen, and other Vulkins from their unneceſſary Employments to be buſied in <hi>Plowing</hi> or <hi>Fiſhing,</hi> or elſe begging, ſteal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing or ſtarving; for I know no reaſon, why they ſhould have fairer Quarter, if it be thought unreaſonable to preſerve the Silk <hi>Manufactory,</hi> which is of far greater advantage to the Nation.</p>
            <p>I am credibly inform'd of one inſtance more which may ſeem amazing, but a ſufficient Teſtimony that they will not fail of doing what I have mention'd; which is, That there is great quantities of <hi>Gold and Silver</hi> Orris, and other <hi>Trimmings</hi> for <hi>Ladies</hi> and Gentlewomens Garments prepared and coming, which conſidering that they have both their <hi>Gold and Silver-Wyar Plate,</hi> and <hi>Thred</hi> from us; or if they have likewiſe car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried the <hi>Art</hi> of <hi>Wire-drawing</hi> our <hi>Crown-pieces</hi> thither, 'tis ſtrange to imagine (That un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs they do firſt <hi>adulterate</hi> it) They can make it worth their while by the differing price of <hi>Silk</hi> and <hi>Workmanſhip</hi> to ſend it hither; but that they preſume the <hi>Engliſh</hi> will over-value <hi>Gold</hi> and <hi>Silver</hi> by <hi>Weight,</hi> Wrought in <hi>India,</hi> as they do <hi>Silks</hi> and <hi>Stufft</hi> by Meaſure; but by theſe means, and the former of <hi>Ribbonds,</hi> the poor Nar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row <hi>Weavers</hi> muſt be in as bad condition as the <hi>Broad;</hi> but that they may carry <hi>Spa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>iſh Wool, Iron, Leather,</hi> and other our groſſer <hi>Materials,</hi> to Manufacture and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn to their greater advantage, is certain, and theſe proceeding are not leſs dange<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous to the body of this <hi>Kingdom</hi> then is unrectified, <hi>Mercury</hi> to the Natural Body of <hi>Men,</hi> for it will in the end <hi>Carode</hi> and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſume us.</p>
            <p>And here I cannot do leſs than take no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice of a paſſage in a late Tract, few Months ſince writ on this occaſion, juſt before the Concluſion of the laſt Seſſions of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, Entitled, <hi>England's Advocate;</hi> which without pretence to a Prophetick Spirit, tells us <hi>page</hi> the 46th, That if the <hi>India Merchants</hi> did not Tranſport Wool, they would doubtleſs Project ſuch Cloths or Stuffs of Silk, Cotton, as ſhould be though ſit for the Uſe of men, to outvye Cloths and Worſted Stuffs; and though the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thor proteſts he knew not that any ſuch were made or coming, they are come, and will doubtleſs farther prove for the enrich<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of <hi>England,</hi> as their Silks, Stuffs, and Painted <hi>Callicoes</hi> have already done; and by this and like means, do <hi>Thouſands</hi> of Broad <hi>Loombs,</hi> and hundreds of <hi>Throwſters</hi> and <hi>Twiſters Mills,</hi> ſtand to <hi>ſpoil</hi> and <hi>burn,</hi> and many <hi>Thouſands</hi> of People forced to Tranſport themſelves, or beg, or ſteal, or ſtarve: Whilſt the great <hi>Mogulls</hi> Subjects are encouraged, and employed, and mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titudes both of <hi>Loombs</hi> and <hi>Mills</hi> made and making to imitate the manner and forms of thoſe <hi>Silks</hi> and <hi>Stuffs</hi> (which like <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>glers Ground-bate</hi>) was lately Expoſed at <hi>Skinners-Hall;</hi> and if thoſe pieces will not afſord variety enough, the 50<hi>l.</hi> worth of <hi>Patterns</hi> lately purchaſed (not any exceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing half a Yard) will doubtleſs ſo direct and inform to make ſuch returns of <hi>Cargoes,</hi> as ſhall make our <hi>Scotch</hi> Brethren decline their attempt for <hi>Gold</hi> at <hi>Darien,</hi> to reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver their loſs, and to ſtrive to grow rich by contradictions as we do, at leaſt thus to furniſh their <hi>Kingdom</hi> with <hi>Silks</hi> for their own uſe, if not to ſpoil their Scotchcloth Trade; and we have reaſon to believe that other parts will avoid our impoſing on them, and that the <hi>Government</hi> will take care that our <hi>Plantations</hi> ſhall advance our <hi>Welfare;</hi> and that no ſmall body of men ſhall be a <hi>Monopoly by Law,</hi> to the undoing the reſt of the <hi>Kingdom;</hi> and that the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king all neceſſary Commodities may not be chiefly transferr'd <hi>to India,</hi> which as things now are, 'tis impoſſible to prevent, unleſs our People may buy Corn as cheap as <hi>Indians</hi> do Rice, and learn to go <hi>Naked,</hi> without catching <hi>cold,</hi> for Peoples labour and our Productions was the original of our <hi>Wealth</hi> and <hi>Trade,</hi> and 'tis they chiefly that muſt ſupport it.</p>
            <p>And for theſe bad purpoſes are many great <hi>Wits</hi> and <hi>Purſes</hi> at Work, to make their <hi>Sons</hi> great, and their Daughters <hi>La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies</hi> and <hi>Dutcheſſes,</hi> by impoveriſhing and diſpeopling the <hi>Kingdom;</hi> for as theſe things are accompliſhing, ſo muſt both our <hi>Wealth</hi>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:61602:4"/>and <hi>Numbers</hi> decreaſe; and if it be cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, that nothing but multitudes of people will maintain the value of Lands; and it is as certain, That as <hi>People</hi> fails, Rent will do ſo alſo. But I believe the damage of the Silk and Stuff <hi>Manufacture</hi> (for which I chiefly contend) is of as great prejudice to the Kingdom, as all the reſt of the evils we may expect, in reſpect of the dependance the <hi>Woollen and Worſted Manufacture</hi> hath upon it; and it hath been proved, That as that of <hi>Silk</hi> decreaſeth, ſo will the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portation of them decreaſe in proportion, and poverty abound. Accordingly amongſt all the aforementioned people.</p>
            <p>One inſtance of which, I had accidental op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portunity to be inform'd in, that the Pariſh of S. <hi>But. Biſhopſg.</hi> whoſe many By-lanes and Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lies being chiefly inhabited by Workers of <hi>Silk</hi> and their dependants, doth ſo abound with Poverty, that for Maintenance and prevention thereof, though their Aſſeſs<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment is doubled upon moſt of their Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants of what they lately uſed to pay to the Poors Rate, they were nevertheleſs, for the laſt Year obliged to pay 34 Months Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſsment thereto, to pay former <hi>Debts,</hi> in the which time, the then <hi>Churchwarden</hi> (though a prudent and honeſt man) at gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving up his Accounts, brought the <hi>Pariſh</hi> indebted for that Year upward of Three <hi>hundred pounds</hi> more; and I doubt not (though I have not opportunity of Inqui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry) but all parts where they inhabit ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to their number, ſuffer alike; all which is the Effects of this <hi>India Trade.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And I am confident in the end (except to the Pattentees) it muſt produce empty Purſes, empty Houſes, empty Towns, a ſmall poor, weak and ſlender people; and what can we imagine will be the value of Lands, as things thus are nothing can prevent ruin, unleſs we have ſuch intereſt in our <hi>European</hi> Confederacy, that they will agree and be contented that <hi>England</hi> ſhall have the ſole Monopoly of this <hi>India</hi> Trade; and that they will be our Cuſtomers, the quite con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary of which every Kingdom and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, whoſe Manufactures they prejudice, are projecting and practiſing.</p>
            <p>The Folly and Error of <hi>England</hi> in this caſe far ſurpaſſeth that of <hi>Eſau</hi> in the ſelling his Birth-right for a Meſs of Pottage; for we give the <hi>Indians</hi> and Pattentees both Fleſh and Pottage, when we ſend our Silver away to purchaſe a Curſe to our ſelves, which their Manufactures are, and after this year of 1700 let us never more Laugh at, and Ridicule the poor Negroe <hi>Indians,</hi> that give us their Gold duſt, which themſelves are not capa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble better to improve; for Beads, Shells, Knives and Sizars, and ſuch like, which are to them for Uſe and Ornament, when we part with our Bullion to inveſt our King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom with <hi>China</hi> Toyes, or obſcene Statues and Images, and other Trifles; but the height of our folly is chiefly expreſt in their Manufactors that are oppoſite to, and deſtructive of our one; nor do I be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve that <hi>Solomon</hi> ſent his Ships purpoſely for; though they brought Peacocks Feathers with their Gold for which they went; but we ſend our Coin to fetch us as meer Toyes as Feathers and to worſe purpoſe as before expreſt.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>SIR,</hi> 'Tis worthy conſideration that abundance of particular Weavers Trades that are deſtroyed both in <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terbury, Norwich</hi> did employ more numbers of people than any <hi>Country</hi> or <hi>Corporation</hi> Workhouſe, though great charge to the publick can poſſibly do; and I will under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>take to demonſtrate, if required, that each of them brought annually greater ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantage to <hi>England,</hi> (all things con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidered) than any <hi>East-India</hi> Ship. But for the <hi>Silk Throwsters,</hi> though not ſo many in Number, there are ſeveral of them that im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy ſuch <hi>multitudes</hi> as are ſcarce to be thought, or credited; and if you will pleaſe to view any of their Workhouſes, as for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly employ'd, ſome of which ſtill re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>main, and with me caſt your thoughts re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trogade, through the <hi>Turky Merchants</hi> Warehouſe, from whence the <hi>Throwſter</hi> re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceives his <hi>Silk,</hi> and by the way it came thi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Plow the Ocean to <hi>Smyrna</hi> in <hi>Turky,</hi> and obſerve his Factor employ'd in produ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cing this in return of our <hi>Engliſh</hi> Cloth, and then return your thoughts back again (with your conſideration, that this Naviga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion is of greater advantage than that of <hi>India.</hi>) And ſuppoſe you ſee in St. <hi>Hellena</hi>'s or <hi>Cornhil,</hi> or <hi>Biſhopſgateſtreet,</hi> the <hi>Turky, Merchants</hi> Warehouſes crouded with thoſe
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:61602:4"/>Cloths prepared for this purpoſe, and the great advantage his Dependants, <hi>Drawers, Dyers, Clotheworkers</hi> make thereon, with whom caſt your Eye through <hi>Blackwel-hall,</hi> and with the Waggon that brought theſe <hi>Cloths</hi> to Town, let your mind travel to any conſiderable Clothiers Workhouſes, in <hi>Worceſter,</hi> or <hi>Gloſterſhire,</hi> and obſerve the numerous and profitable employ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, before you come to the Loomb ſide to ſee the <hi>Shuttle,</hi> and you will not grudge the poor Weavers that Shutes it 5<hi>s.</hi> per week for his labour Then look on to the leſs profitable employment of <hi>Shifting, Carding,</hi> and <hi>Spinning,</hi> till we come to the Shearing Houſe of this <hi>Gol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den Fleece,</hi> and then return your Conſideration back to one of the beforementioned <hi>Throwſters Shops,</hi> and I will be obliged plainly to demon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrate, that ſo much of theſe Operations, when Wrought in Cloth, as make return in <hi>Turky Silk</hi> for the employment of this one Silk Throwſter; which being farther improv'd in <hi>Weaving, Stockin-Making,</hi> &amp;c. will gain annually greater profit to <hi>England,</hi> than ever any whole Fleet from <hi>Eaſt India</hi> did or can (if you conſider the da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage they likewiſe do) and I believe that on theſe, or the like Conſiderations, did the Wiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of this Nation think fit by Law, to prohibit the bringing over of Silk ready <hi>Thrown</hi> or <hi>Dyed;</hi> which Laws are rendred utterly ineffectual, and theſe Trades with the Weavers deſtroyed, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs prevention of the home Conſumption of <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Figur'd, Flower'd, and Stript Silks be granted, which is all the Silk-Weavers and Silk-Throwſters deſire.</p>
            <p>For by what hath been (now and for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly) ſaid, 'tis certain that the <hi>Living Bodies</hi> of people are the beſt <hi>Riches</hi> and <hi>Strength</hi> any Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try can be poſſeſſed of; and that all Manufactu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring parts of <hi>Europe</hi> (eſpecially <hi>England</hi>) deſtroy both their People and Land by admiſſion of Trading in <hi>India</hi> Manufacturers.</p>
            <p n="2">II, 'Tis impoſſible any Kingdom can enjoy this bleſſing of <hi>people</hi> without procuring or al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing them <hi>Imployment</hi> and <hi>Wages</hi> for their Subſiſtence, anſwerable to the price of <hi>Proviſions</hi> and all other Neceſſaries of <hi>Life.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="3">III. That no <hi>Manufacture,</hi> (excepting that of <hi>Wool</hi>) maintains or employs ſo many peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple as the <hi>Silk Weavers,</hi> and the <hi>Silk Throwſters,</hi> with their dependants, who are not to be num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber'd; and that as the Silk and Grogram-Yarn Manufactures in <hi>England</hi> decreaſeth, the Woollen will likewiſe in proportion.</p>
            <p n="4">IV. That all <hi>Engliſh Silk Manufactures</hi> work for as ſmall Wages as will ſupport Life.</p>
            <p n="5">V. That whatever pretences are made of purchaſing <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Wrought <hi>Silks</hi> with any thing, but our money is either falſe or frivolous.</p>
            <p n="6">VI. That the Silk Manufacturers ask not near ſo much as 'tis greatly reaſonable ſhould be granted, both for the Kingdom and their own good; which is a total prohibition of the Uſe and Conſumption of all <hi>India</hi> Wrought Silks and Stuffs whatſoever, both Figured and Plain, or Painted in all our <hi>Engliſh</hi> Dominions and Plantations, and then we ſhould not want Workhouſes for the Imployment of our poor in Country or City, nor the <hi>Turky</hi> or <hi>Italian</hi> Merchants want Vend for their Cloths and Stuffs Abroad, or Silk at Home.</p>
            <p>To Conclude; <hi>Engliſh</hi> Tradeſmen may bleſs God that our Laws are alterable, not like thoſe of the <hi>Medes</hi> and <hi>Perſians,</hi> elſe they would be in little better condition than were the poor <hi>Jews</hi> under the contrivance and patent of the wicked <hi>Hammond;</hi> for doubtleſs thoſe <hi>Jews</hi> might within the limited time fly for their Lives, and ſo muſt theſe Manufactures, or do worſe, or ſtarve, as Multitudes have already done, if not by Law relieved. From all which Evils, I pray God to incline the hearts of thoſe that Govern, to deliver us, and for God's ſake, Sir, I beg that your aſſiſtance may not be wanting.</p>
            <closer>
               <date>
                  <hi>Jan. the Firſt,</hi> 1699.</date>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
               <signed>I am Yours</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="postscript">
            <pb facs="tcp:61602:5"/>
            <head>POSTSCRIPT.</head>
            <p>THERE are now no leſs than 50 Ships coming from, at, and on their way to <hi>India;</hi> which, conſidering the Silver they have carried out, and the Manufactures they will re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn upon us, is an Amazing Conſideration to all that value the Preſervation of OLD ENGLAND. For 'tis plain, That ſince we are become ſuch Excellent Cuſtomers for their <hi>China</hi> and <hi>Bengal</hi> Wrought Silks and Stuffs, they have the Wiſdom to ſerve us with lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle but the very traſh of Raw-Silk, or ſuperfine Cotton, or Yarn, to employ our poor, whoſe working and preſervation (whatever ſome judge) is a greater and ſurer Teſtimony of the good Trade of the Kingdom, than our own inriching the Cuſtom-houſe Coffers by payment of great Duties for the Importation of ſuch Manufactures as the 50 or any of the like ſort ſhall hereafter Import.</p>
            <p>Since this was compos'd, there is one of the 50 above-mentioned arriv'd,, ('tis named the <hi>Riſing Eagle;</hi>) and though Four days ſince, no Cargo yet publick: But common Roport ſays, ſhe brought 97 Cheſts of Wrought Silks, and not one pound of Raw.</p>
            <p>That the undone Broad Figured Silk Weavers both of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Canterbury</hi> that have al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready laid down their Trade, and their Mountures ſpoil'd, and their Harneſſes Rotten, can never venter to remount their Loombs on any other ſecurity than a future Prohibition as re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quir'd (which may be made as ſecure as the Payment of any great Duty) and which, if not granted, will occaſion the ſinking of thoſe that remain to the utter loſs of that Manufactor in <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:61602:5"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
